

105 Johnston Ave. Toronto. Ontario

□ (647) 292-4223 | ■ gabechan@alumni.uwaterloo.ca | 回 gabecchan | 回 gabecchan

Skills

Technology Delivery 15+ years with experience in helpdesk, business analysis, development lead, test lead, devops and project management

Financial Services 8 years with experience in Anti-Money Laundering (AML), Fraud, Basel, Debit & Credit Cards, Settlement and reconciliation,

Lending and Call Centres

Oil & Gas Hugo, Redux, React, HTML5, LESS, SASS

Technology Working knowledge of Azure, Agile (Scrum & Kanban) Linux, Windows, Mainframe, SQL Server, Oracle, ETL, APIs, Office 365

including Power BI, Power Automate

Summary_

Current Site Reliability Engineer at start-up company Kasa. 7+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and computer hacking/security. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience

Suncor Mississauga, Ontario

Manager, DevOps

June 2020 - Present

 Provisioned an easily managable hybrid infrastructure (Amazon AWS + On-premise) utilizing IaC (Infrastructure as Code) tools like Ansible, Packer and Terraform

- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on CircleCI for containerized applications using Docker, AWS ECR and Rancher.
- Designed an overall service architecture and pipelines of the Machine Learning based Fashion Tagging API SaaS product with the micro-services architecture.
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js Koa and in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.
- Deployed a centralized logging environment(ELK, Filebeat, CloudWatch, S3) which gather log data from docker containers and AWS resources.
- Deployed a centralized monitoring environment(Grafana, InfluxDB, CollectD) which gather system metrics as well as docker run-time metrics.

Suncor Mississauga, Ontario

MANAGER, QUALITY MANAGEMENT

May 2019 - June 2020

- Implemented RESTful API server for car rental booking application(CARPLAT in Google Play).
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, CircleCI, and several AWS stack(Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- · Developed an easy-to-use Payment module which connects to major PG(Payment Gateway) companies in Korea.

Suncor Mississauga, Ontario

QUALITY MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST - DOWNSTREAM & TECHNICAL TESTING

Oct 2015 - May 2019

- Lead engineer on agent-less backtracking system that can discover client device's fingerprint(including public and private IP) independently of the Proxy, VPN and NAT.
- Implemented a distributed web stress test tool with high anonymity.
- Implemented a military cooperation system which is web based real time messenger in Scala on Lift.

Suncor Mississauga, Ontario

QUALITY MANAGEMENT TEST COORDINATOR

July 2011 - Sept 2015

- Developed in Cocos2d-x an action puzzle game(Dragon Buster) targeting U.S. market.
- Implemented API server which is communicating with game client and In-App Store, along with two other team members who wrote the game logic and designed game graphics.
- Won the 2nd prize in final evaluation.

CIBC - Remote Banking and Shared Services

Toronto, Ontario

Fraud Test Consultant (Contract)

Feb 2010 - July 2011

- Developed a proxy drive smartphone application which connects proxy driver and customer.
- Implemented overall Android application logic and wrote API server for community service, along with lead engineer who designed bidding protocol on raw socket and implemented API server for bidding.

CIBC Retail Markets Toronto, Ontario

VISA DEBIT: UAT TEST MANAGER (CONTRACT)

Feb 2009 – Jan 2010

- Responsible for managing the User Acceptance Test (UAT) across multiple business groups as part of the launch of the first VISA Debit product into the Canadian marketplace
- Coordinated program testing across tests for card issuance, point-of-sale transactions, settlement and reconciliation, disputes & charge backs and loyalty program enrollment & fulfillment

Accenture Toronto, Ontario

TEST CONSULTANT (CONTRACT)

Nov 2008 - Dec 2008

Accenture Toronto, Ontario

FINANCIAL SERVICES CONSULTANT

Sept 2003 - Oct 2008

- PROJECT MANAGER Coordinated program testing across tests for card issuance, point-of-sale transactions, settlement and reconciliation, disputes & charge backs and loyalty program enrollment & fulfillment
- DEVELOPMENT LEAD Coordinated program testing across tests for card issuance, point-of-sale transactions, settlement and reconciliation, disputes & charge backs and loyalty program enrollment & fulfillment
- BUSINESS ANALYST Coordinated program testing across tests for card issuance, point-of-sale transactions, settlement and reconciliation, disputes & charge backs and loyalty program enrollment & fulfillment
- TEST LEAD Coordinated program testing across tests for card issuance, point-of-sale transactions, settlement and reconciliation, disputes & charge backs and loyalty program enrollment & fulfillment

Additional Experience Variou

CO-OP INTERNSHIPS 1997 - 2002

· Marketing and technology roles at Microsoft Canada, Bell Canada, Cisco Systems, Dofasco, Delano Technology Corp, and Aird & Berlis LLP

Education

Schulich School of Business, York University

Toronto, Ontario

MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

2011 - 2014

University of Waterloo Waterloo, Ontario

HONOURS BACHELOR OF APPLIED SCIENCE: SYSTEMS DESIGN ENGINEERING

1998 - 2003

· Minor in Economics, Option in Management Science

Hillfield Strathallan College

Hamilton, Ontario

ONTARIO SECONDARY SCHOOL DIPLOMA

1982 - 1998

Courses & Certifications

Mar 2021 Microsoft, Azure Al Fundamentals (Certified)

Toronto, Ontario

Feb 2021 John Hopkins University, A Crash Course in Data Science

Toronto, Ontario

Oct 2019 Microsoft, Azure Fundamentals (Certified)

Toronto, Ontario

Sept 2018 **Disciplined Agile Consortium**, Disciplined Agile Delivery (DA 101)

Calgary, Alberta